لَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا رُسُلَنَا بِالْبَيِّنَاتِ وَأَنْزَلْنَا مَعَهُمُ الْكِتَابَ وَالْمِيزَانَ لِيَقُومَ
النَّاسُ بِالْقِسْطِ وَأَنْزَلْنَا الْحَدِيدَ فِيهِ بَأْسٌ شَدِيدٌ وَمَنَافِعُ لِلنَّاسِ
وَلِيَعْلَمَ اللهَُّ مَنْ يَنْصُرُهُ وَرُسُلَهُ بِالْغَيْبِ إِنَّ اللهََّ قَوِيٌّ عَزِيزٌ (الحديد ٢٥)
And We certainly sent Our messengers with
clear proofs, and We sent down with them the
Scripture and the Balance, that mankind may
uphold justice. And We sent down iron in which
there is intense force and benefits for humanity,
and that Allah may know who supports Him and
His messengers, though unseen. Indeed, Allah is All-Powerful, Almighty. (Qur’an 57:25)
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آَمَنُوا كُونُوا قَوَّامِينَ بِالْقِسْطِ شُهَدَاءَ للهَِِّ وَلَوْ عَلَى أَنْفُسِكُمْ أَوِ
الْوَالِدَيْنِ وَالْأَقْرَبِينَ إِنْ يَكُنْ غَنِيًّا أَوْ فَقِيرًا فَاللهَُّ أَوْلَى بِهِمَا فَلَا تَتَّبِعُوا الْهَوَى أَنْ
تَعْدِلُوا وَإِنْ تَلْوُوا أَوْ تُعْرِضُوا فَإِنَّ اللهََّ كَانَ بِمَا تَعْمَلُونَ خَبِيرًا (النساء ١٣٥ )
O you who have attained faith! Stand firmly for justice,
as witnesses to Allah, even if against yourselves, or
your parents, or your relatives. Whether a person is rich
or poor, Allah is worthier as a patron of both. So do not
follow prejudice, so as to do justice; but if you twist, or
turn away, then indeed Allah has always been All-Aware of what you do. (Qur'an 4:135)
الْيَوْمَ تُجْزَى كُلُّ نَفْسٍ بِمَا كَسَبَتْ لَا ظُلْمَ الْيَوْمَ إِنَّ اللهََّ سَرِيعُ الْحِسَابِ ( 17 غافر)
Today, every soul is repaid for what it has earned. There is no injustice today; indeed, Allah is swift in reckoning. (Qur'an 40:17)
"If the Final Hour comes while you are planting a little palm tree then try to plant it quickly before the hour." (Hadeeth Sahih Al-Albany)